Yueun Kim

★ yueunkim.dev in yueunk yueunk Denver, CO yk@yueunkim.dev

Summary

I am a full-stack software engineer with a passion for collaborating to solve challenging problems. I have experience with the JavaScript, Ruby, and Go ecosystems. Most recently, I created Cascade ☑, an open-source containerized application deployment solution with automated observability built with Node.js/Express, OpenTelemetry, React, and Terraform CDK for TypeScript.

Experience

2022 – present

Creator, Software Engineer

Cascade (https://try-cascade.github.io □)

- Led an ideation process of prototyping Cascade, an open-source containerized application deployment solution with built-in support for observability
- Built an NPM package for tracing instrumentation compatible with AWS Distro for OpenTelemetry Collector and AWS X-Ray
- Constructed Cascade's Backend API to collaborate with the Terraform CDK and Cascade Frontend to automate deployment in a 3-step process
- Developed a GUI that allows users to deploy and destroy their containerized applications with one click and view resource creation statuses real-time via SSE
- Automated deployment using Docker (images, docker-compose)
- Authored a comprehensive technical case study on design decisions and challenges of building Cascade
- Collaborated with a remote team of 4 engineers across 3 timezones using agile workflow

2020 - 2022

Software Engineer

Open-source web applications and Launch School experience

- Developed open-source software using Ruby, Node.js, Express, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HTML/CSS, and more
- Selected projects:
 - Yarn Basket: a real-time webhook debugging tool with custom endpoints (Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, DigitalOcean Droplet, Nginx, PM2)
 - The Shoppe: a database-backed e-commerce app (Node, React, MongoDB, Docker)
 - Flight Tracker: an SVG map for filtering and viewing airline routes (React, Docker)

2014 - 2020

Director of Piano Performance

Vivaldi Music Academy

Crafted curricula for the piano department, trained piano instructors, and conducted
masterclasses and private lessons contributing to the highest growth rate in academy
history expanding from one to four locations in the Greater Houston area

Skills

Backend

Node.js, Express, Ruby, Go, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful APIs

Frontend

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Jest, HTML/CSS, Tailwind CSS

Tooling

Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux, Bash, OpenTelemetry, AWS (S3, SQS, EC2, ECS), Terraform

Education

Rice University, Master of Music, Piano Chamber Music

Northwestern University, Master of Music, Piano Performance and Pedagogy

Eastman School of Music, Bachelor of Music, Piano Performance